<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on joji_fx blog</title><link>https://dearalgorithm.github.io/joji_fx/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on joji_fx blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 17:30:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dearalgorithm.github.io/joji_fx/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Khan Academy trig functions test</title><link>https://dearalgorithm.github.io/joji_fx/04-khan-academy-trig-functions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 17:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dearalgorithm.github.io/joji_fx/04-khan-academy-trig-functions/</guid><description>After months of hard work, finally I have 100% in the Khan Academy Trigonometry section. This was my last exam, which I had to take it several times before reaching the ace!
With my new knowledge I&amp;rsquo;ll try to code a unit circle animation and publish it in a new post.</description></item><item><title>A very brief history of abstraction</title><link>https://dearalgorithm.github.io/joji_fx/03-a-very-brief-history-of-abstraction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 13:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dearalgorithm.github.io/joji_fx/03-a-very-brief-history-of-abstraction/</guid><description>Hi computers,
I have been thinking about abstraction and I would like to share my thoughts with you. Let’s first of all define what I understand about abstraction, in computer science terms.
First definition:
An abstract definition of something is something that is as undefined as possible but can potentially be infinitely defined.
A less abstract version of First definition:
An abstract definition of something (x|object) is something (x|object) that is as undefined as possible (according to the current base knowledge) but can potentially be infinitely defined.</description></item><item><title>long long time no C*! (type journal essay)</title><link>https://dearalgorithm.github.io/joji_fx/02-long-long-time-no-c/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 17:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dearalgorithm.github.io/joji_fx/02-long-long-time-no-c/</guid><description>Well, hi! How are you human/computer? I really hope there are no under voltage warnings in your log. What have I been doing all this time? Well, mainly, I&amp;rsquo;ve been chewing gum and making pretty bubbles with it (which ended up popping over my whole face) and contemplating this mad world with my hands in my pockets.
(Pretty much like this)
credits: bubblegumkids.xyz
Okay, I was kidding! Actually the most remarkable thing that I achieved last months is (drumroll…) I learnt React!</description></item><item><title>How to backup files remotely from Fedora Server 34 to Fedora Workstation 34</title><link>https://dearalgorithm.github.io/joji_fx/01-remote-backups-with-fedora-and-rsnapshot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 20:30:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dearalgorithm.github.io/joji_fx/01-remote-backups-with-fedora-and-rsnapshot/</guid><description>Things you will need:
An internet connection or a local area network A computer/virtual machine with Fedora Workstation installed A computer/virtual machine with Fedora Server Installed Let’s assume that you have a Fedora Workstation 34 machine with the purpose of saving backups on it.
Also, you have a Fedora Server 34. You know the root’s password and you checked Allow root SSH login with password during the installation.
If you need to add your username to sudoers, reboot the machine, log in as root and type usermod -aG wheel yourusername</description></item><item><title>How to install Ubuntu Server on a Raspberry Pi 4 model B in 3 steps (The easiest way)</title><link>https://dearalgorithm.github.io/joji_fx/00-ubuntu-server-raspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 15:34:20 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dearalgorithm.github.io/joji_fx/00-ubuntu-server-raspberry-pi/</guid><description>Things you need:
A Raspberry Pi 4 model B An Ethernet Cable A proper power supply for your Raspberry Pi An SD Card compatible with your Raspberry I’m assuming that you already have a computer with an SD card slot and an internet connection.
I will be using a laptop with Fedora 34 workstation as an “external computer”. But you can follow these steps if you are on other distributions, MacOS or Windows.</description></item></channel></rss>